‎NETFLIX 呈献
‎进攻！
Attack!
‎快 快点 冲出去！
Go! Come on! Faster!
‎快上梯子！
‎冲出去！
‎海因里希 来 快冲啊！
Heinrich, come on! Forwards! Come now!
‎我们走！
To the ladders!
‎快上梯子！
‎听我的命令！
On my command!
‎-冲啊！ ‎-汉斯？
Forwards!
‎快进攻！给我冲出去！
Heinrich! Get out there!
‎快！冲啊！
All of you, go!
‎汉斯？
Come on! Get out of there!
‎-汉斯？ ‎-快点 海因里希！
Go, Heinrich! Get out there now!
‎快冲上去！
‎进攻！
Attack!
‎快点！
Go! Forwards!
‎快啊！
‎快点 再快点！
‎快找掩护！
‎海因里希！
Heinrich!
-Attack! Attack! -Attack!
‎片名：西线无战事
ALL QUIET ON THE WESTERN FRONT
Come on!
‎（海因里希葛柏）
‎（德国北部 1917年春）
NORTHERN GERMANY SPRING 1917
‎（战争第三年）
THIRD YEAR OF WAR
‎-保罗！ ‎-保罗！
Paul! Paul!
‎保罗 喂
-Paul! Well? -So?
‎怎么样？
Mhm.
‎不行
‎那怎么办？
-Well then? -I don't know.
‎不知道
‎-他知道我们都会去吗？ ‎-当然了
-Does he know we're all going? -Yes, of course.
‎你要待在家里吗？
Staying at home?
‎我的天 你是听妈妈话的小宝宝呀？
My God, you're tied to your mother's apron strings, my friend.
‎来 我帮你签
Give me it, I'll scribble something.
‎要他父母签才行
-It has to be signed by his parents. -Well, someone. Come on, pass it here.
‎可他们没签啊 快给我
‎不行的 会被发现的
-That won't work, they'll find out. -How will they?
‎怎么可能？
Well?
‎怎么会发现？
Is his mother a pen pal of theirs?
‎他们和他爸是笔友吗？
‎把你的笔给我
-Give me your pen. -Ah, I'm sorry.
‎我没有
Oh!
‎路德维希
Ludwig.
‎你会有麻烦的 他会暴打你一顿
You mustn't. Your father will hit you.
‎你有更好的主意吗？
Have you got a better idea? I'm not being left behind here.
‎总不能我一个人留下啊
‎太好了！
Jawohl!
‎恭喜你 博伊默尔列兵 你要上前线了
Congratulations, Private Bäumer. We're going to the front.
‎我死定了
A dead man walking.
‎你们即将步入人生的新阶段
You stand here on the threshold of existence.
‎记住这一刻！
Remember this moment.
‎这是个很重要的时刻
It is a great moment.
‎将来别人对你们的评价会取决于
For in years to come, you will be judged based on what you dared to become today.
‎你们今日的勇气和作为
‎钢铁般的德意志青年们
The iron youth of Germany.
‎我的朋友们
My friends,
‎我们很幸运得以生在这个伟大的时代
we are fortunate to be alive at a great time.
‎你们的行动将化作生命之源
Your deeds will be the water
‎滋养强壮而高贵的根茎
nourishing the growth of a strong and noble route.
‎站好认真听 莱尼曼！
Stand still and listen up, Leinemann!
‎皇帝陛下需要的是士兵 不是孩子
The Kaiser needs soldiers, not children.
‎我相信我很快能见到
I am certain that I will see most of you again soon, here at home.
‎你们中的大部分人归来
‎你们将带着荣耀归剑入鞘
Your sword returned to its scabbard with honour and respect.
‎你们骄傲高挺的胸前会佩戴着铁十字
A cross crafted from iron proudly displayed upon your chest.
‎但是不要搞错了
However, take heed of this.
‎在最黑暗的时刻
In the darkest of hours, let me assure you it will happen,
‎在你们等待进攻之时
‎你们可能会心生疑虑
that prior to an attack, you will harbour doubts.
‎但这不是薄志弱行的时候！
But this is not the time to concede to any mental weakness.
‎任何犹豫和迟疑都是对祖国的背叛！
Any unsteadiness, any hesitation is a betrayal of the fatherland!
‎现代战争就像一盘棋局
For modern war is like a game of chess.
‎关键从来不在个人
It is never about an individual soldier.
‎最重要的一直都是整体
Our only care is for the entirety of the body.
‎你们将证明自己配得上这身制服
You have the chance to earn the right to wear the uniforms you have been given.
‎突破敌人在法兰德斯的战线
And by going to the front line in Flanders, we'll pierce the enemy.
‎在那之后
And then you will, in a few short weeks,
‎就再过几个星期
‎你们就会挺进巴黎了！
finally march on Paris!
‎好！
Yeah!
‎我们的未来
Our future,
‎德国的未来
the future of Deutschland,
‎掌握在最伟大的一代人手中
lies in the hands of its greatest generation.
‎我的朋友们
My friends, that is you, you see!
‎那就是你们！
Yeah!
‎对！
Therefore, off to the camps
‎那么 去战斗吧！
‎为了皇帝、上帝和祖国！
for the Kaiser, God, and the fatherland!
‎好！
Yeah!
‎-太棒了！ ‎-好！
‎下一个
Next.
-Next. -Next.
‎保罗博伊默尔 维森格伦德53号
Bäumer, Paul. 53 Wiesengrund.
‎1899年11月18日生
Born November 18th, 1899. Correct?
‎对吗？
Jawohl, sir.
‎对 长官
Next.
‎保罗？
Paul.
‎给
Here. Your father can be proud of you.
‎你父亲会为你感到骄傲
Yes.
‎对
‎一切还好吗？
Is everything alright?
‎对 我就是等不及了
Yes. I'm eager to get on with it.
‎下一个
Move along.
‎你走吧
‎下一个
Here he comes.
-Emil Hermann. -Name and address.
‎不好意思
-And the next. -Excuse me.
‎这是别人的
It already belongs to someone.
‎下一个
Ah, yes. It was probably too small for the fellow. Happens all the time.
‎啊 可能这家伙穿起来太小了
‎这是常有的事
Here. It's yours.
‎来 祝一切顺利
‎谢谢
Thank you.
‎（海因里希葛柏）
‎天啊 就像量身定做的似的
I remember it, you were.
‎喂 路德维希 这下你姑娘随便找了？
Oh, Ludwig, will you be snatching away all the ladies from us now?
‎对
Yeah.
‎只要你不开枪打我们就行
My concern is that you don't shoot us.
‎姑娘 我爱你 我真的爱你
‎但我还不能够娶你
‎再等一年吧 就会…
‎她不会等的 弗朗茨
She won't wait, Franz.
‎她不会等的
She won't do it.
‎你这个少女杀手
You lady killer, you.
‎喝下茶一杯 还有糖和咖啡
‎再来红酒一杯
‎姑娘 我爱你 我真的爱你
‎但我还不能够娶你
‎再等一年吧 就会成真了
‎（法国北部 拉马尔迈松 ‎距西线25公里）
LA MALMAISON, NORTHERN FRANCE 25 KM TO THE WESTERN FRONT
‎这位士兵 你叫什么名字？
-Your name? -Kropp. Albert Kropp, sir.
‎克罗普 阿尔伯特克罗普 中尉
‎你喜欢肮脏的姑娘吗 克罗普？
Do you like dirty girls, Kropp?
‎你喜不喜欢肮脏的姑娘？
Do you like dirty girls?
‎不喜欢 中尉
Uh, no. I don't, sir.
‎那你怎么捧着肮脏的枪睡？
So why do you sleep with one then?
‎凌晨3点去站岗放哨
Report for guard duty at three o'clock.
‎各位 你们的战斗地点如同粪坑
Gentlemen, you'll be fighting in a godforsaken shithole.
‎你们的G98步枪最好干干净净的
And you'll kindly do so with a clean G98.
‎你们要细心呵护它
You will pamper it.
‎好好爱它
You will love it.
‎它要像他妈的圣母的大腿一样干净
And damn it, you will keep it as immaculate
as the thighs of the Holy Virgin.
‎明白了吗？
Do we understand each other?
‎遵命！
-Jawohl, sir! -Jawohl, sir!
‎欢迎加入第78步兵预备团
Welcome to the 78th Reserve Infantry Regiment.
‎我们现在在西线
We are now on the Western Front.
‎欢迎来到巴黎！
-Welcome to Paris! -Yeah! Welcome to Paris!
‎太好了！
Ah!
Down there! Down there!
Down there! This way!
This way!
-Go on! Over there on the right! -Damn it, what happened?
‎妈的 怎么回事？
‎我有命令要在傍晚6点前把连队送到
I have orders to hand over the company to the front by 6:00 p.m.
‎可以 但您得步行
That you may, but on foot.
‎我们需要这辆卡车 中尉
You must give us the trucks, lieutenant.
‎恕我直言 我的命令…
With all due respect, I have orders--
‎我他妈去你的命令！
Take the orders and stick them up your arse.
‎我有40个人在泥里奄奄一息
I have 40 men here who are dying in the mud.
‎马上给我下车！
Get out right now, will you?
‎所有人都下车！
Everyone, get up.
‎快点 赶紧的
Come on, get on with it.
‎你们听到军医说的了
You heard the staff surgeon.
‎快点 士兵们 别在这儿睡着了！
Faster, soldiers. Don't fall asleep here.
‎快点！
Keep moving.
‎弗朗茨穆勒 是吗？
-Franz Müller, correct? -Yes.
‎对
The supreme army command
‎总指挥官指望你能至少活六个礼拜
expects you to survive at least six weeks of being here.
‎你想六周后还活着吗？
Would you like that, in six weeks, to still be alive?
‎想 中尉
-Jawohl, sir. -Then walk quicker
‎那就快走 别给我拖拖拉拉的！
and stop dragging your feet like you would do at home.
‎听见没有？
-Do you understand? -Yes.
‎是！
‎快点！
Hurry up.
‎这不是休闲茶会！
We're not at a tea party here.
‎毒气！
Gas!
‎-毒气！ ‎-毒气！
-Gas! -Gas!
‎毒气！
Gas!
‎快戴上防毒面具！
Gas masks on!
‎各位
That, gentlemen, was a fat pig.
‎刚才那个是个大炮弹
‎如果法国人再瞄准一点的话
If the French could aim better,
‎他们就可以拿勺子把我们从路边挖走
you could scrape us all off the road with a spoon and bury us in a saucepan.
‎把我们埋进铁饭盒里了
‎但有一件事是毋庸置疑的
But one thing that's as certain as amen in church.
‎大炮弹是没有毒气的
Fat pigs don't carry gas.
‎向前看！
Eyes straight ahead.
‎你是听不见吗？
-Are you deaf? -No, sir.
‎不是 中尉
I was just trying to put my mask on.
‎我只是忙着戴上防毒面具
‎你 保罗博伊默尔 基本上活不过天亮
Paul Bäumer, you will almost certainly be dead by dawn.
‎你他妈的去吃点东西吧
You should eat something, man.
‎听我口令 摘下防毒面具！
Attention! Gas masks off!
‎摘下防毒面具！
Gas masks off!
‎你别摘
Not you.
‎你戴到今晚值班放哨为止
You keep yours on until guard duty tonight.
‎和那个笨蛋一起
Both you and that useless pig.
‎列队！
Fall in line. March.
‎行进！
Fall in line!
‎大家跟紧点 快走！
Stay together and keep moving!
‎抓紧时间 快点！
Come on, hurry up!
Go!
‎保罗！
Come on. Paul, come on. Give me your knapsack.
‎来 把你的背包给我
‎下次你可以帮我背
Next time, you carry mine.
‎恭喜你们 士兵们
Congratulations, soldiers.
‎这是你们的新家
This is your home now.
‎摘掉头盔！
Helmets off.
‎看来我不在时这里很热闹 斯坦伯格
I see the men have been enjoying themselves in my absence, Steinberger.
‎我们整晚都被炮火轰炸
We were under barrage all night.
‎大家都要崩溃了
The men are a mess.
‎干燥的靴子会是一剂良药
I think dry boots would be a good place to begin.
‎你想让我们都淹死吗？
Oh, you'd rather we all drown then?
‎大家都出把力 把战壕里的水舀出去
Everyone pitch in! Come on, bail out the trench.
Get in line to bail the water!
‎你还在等什么 博伊默尔？
What are you waiting for, Bäumer?
‎还杵在那儿干什么？
Why are you still loitering here? Go and help bail out the trenches.
‎不用站岗的士兵快点舀水
‎给狗扔一块肉
Throw a dog a piece of meat.
Come on, all of you!
‎肯定会被叼走
It will always snap it up.
‎给人一点权力的话
Give a man power
‎他会变得野蛮
Man is a beast.
‎喝吧
Drink.
‎凯特因斯基 过来 帮忙舀水
Katczinsky, come over here. Give us a hand.
‎我们今晚会遭到猛攻
Tonight, it'll be even worse.
‎对不起
Sorry.
‎别说了
Forget it.
‎这跟我想象中的不一样
Somehow, this isn't how I imagined it.
‎闭嘴 路德维希
Just shut up, Ludwig.
‎我的手 我的手没知觉了
My hands. I can't feel my hands any more.
‎把手伸进内裤里
Stick them down your underwear.
‎我就是这样做的
It always works for me.
‎你觉得这样会有利于射击吗？
That will make it shoot better, will it?
‎你听到了吗？
-Did you hear that? -Hear what?
‎什么？
‎那个声音 你听
That sound. Listen.
‎什么都没有
There's nothing there.
‎我们的第一个法国人
Our first French to shoot.
‎冷静点 小保罗
Calm down, Paulchen.
‎我也听到了
There's someone out there.
‎是谁？
Who's there?
‎嘿
Hey.
‎现身吧！
Show yourself!
‎不好！
Oh, no, no, no!
‎我中枪了！
I'm hit! I'm hit! I've been hit! Get off!
‎不 保罗 不要啊
-No, Paul. No. -What's going on?
‎怎么回事？
You're fine.
‎不好了
‎怎么回事？
What is it?
‎那边的人朝我开枪
The others, over there. They shot at me.
‎他们看到你的枪口闪光了
They saw the flash of your muzzle.
‎低调一点
Huh?
‎不想接住下一颗子弹 就往左挪10米
From now on, keep your heads down.
If you don't want to catch the next bullet with your teeth,
‎开枪 移动 再开枪 再移动 懂了吗？
move ten meters to the left.
Shoot, change cover. Shoot, change cover. Understand?
‎懂了
Yeah.
‎来
Come on. Paul.
‎快找掩护！
Take cover! Take cover! Alarm!
‎进来！
Here!
‎博伊默尔 克罗普 你俩快进来 快！
Bäumer, come here. Quickly, come on.
‎快进地堡！
Into the bunker!
‎快进去！
Inside! Inside! Inside!
‎“吃东西小心点”
"Be careful what you eat."
‎我母亲是这么叮嘱我的
That's what my mother said.
‎我们不离不弃 对吧？
-We'll always be together, won't we? -Yeah.
‎-对？ ‎-不离不弃
We'll stick together. We'll always be.
‎对
‎我做不到 保罗
I can't do this, Paul. I can't do this. I need to go home.
‎我做不到 我想回家
‎-嘘 ‎-我想回家
I need to go home.
‎这是徐进弹幕
Creeping barrage.
‎什么？
What?
‎每隔几分钟 炮火就会往前移
Every couple of minutes,
the artillery barrage makes an advance forward.
‎而紧随其后的
And directly after that,
‎就是前进的步兵
the infantry moves forward.
‎这是什么意思？
What are you saying, exactly?
‎他们来了
That's how they come.
‎你去哪里？
Where are you going?
‎我马上回来
I'll come back.
‎弹幕就快结束了
It's nearly over.
‎-不 让我走 ‎-冷静
-No! Let me go. -Stay where you are.
‎-放我出去 我想离开这里 ‎-冷静！
-Let me out of here. I want to get out. -Calm down.
‎冷静
Calm yourself.
‎不要！
No!
‎出去！
Get out! Out! Out! Out!
‎快出去！
Out!
‎快走！出去！
‎出去！
‎大家都出去！
‎保罗 那是保罗
Hey, that's Paul!
‎阿尔伯特！
Albert!
‎阿尔伯特 我们找到保罗了！
Come here, we found Paul!
‎我们得把那根木梁移开
‎保罗
Paul!
‎你没事吧？
Are you alright?
‎还好吗 保罗？
Is everything alright, Paul?
‎来 保罗 起来
Come on. Paul, come on.
‎我来扶你
I'll help you.
‎来 起来 坐起来
Come on. Get up, will you? Sit down.
‎-你受伤了吗？ ‎-继续
Are you injured?
‎保罗 你有没有受伤？
Paul, are you injured?
‎-能听到吗？ ‎-阿尔伯特克罗普 快来帮忙
-Can you hear me? -We need help over here!
‎-回头见 保罗 ‎-回头见 保罗
-See you later, Paul. -We'll see you later, Paul.
Go on! Go on!
Here's another one.
We need help!
Steady.
That's it.
I've got you.
Careful, careful.
Now we're in camp. Sit down.
You're alright.
Nice one. Let's have a look at you.
Hold still, hold still.
Yeah, you're going to be alright.
Right, put pressure on it. Don't let him get up.
‎凯特因斯基 赶紧的
Katczinsky, back to work.
‎你呢？有没有受伤？
And you? Are you injured?
‎没有
No.
‎那就开始收集吧
Then start gathering.
‎天啊！
Man, man, man!
No rest for the wicked.
‎努力才有收获
It's the same every day.
‎快点 都给我抓紧了！
Come on! Keep working!
‎这样下去 后天都完不成
We don't have all day.
‎姓阿布雷希特 名卡尔
Albrecht, Karl. Diepholz.
‎（18个月后）
18 MONTHS LATER
‎来自迪普霍尔茨
September 14th, 1898.
‎出生日期1898年9月14日
‎姓布鲁门塔尔
Blumenthal, Samuel.
‎名萨缪尔
‎来自德累斯顿
Dresden. November 6th, 1900.
‎出生日期1900年11月6日
‎昨天是他的生日
Yesterday was his birthday.
‎姓冯加尔维茨 名古斯塔夫
Von Gallwitz, Gustav.
‎奥斯纳布吕克
Osnabrück, June 20th, '99.
‎1899年6月20日
‎戈茨吕特威茨…
Götz Lüttwitz--
‎够了
That's enough.
‎（陆军最高司令部 1918年11月7日）
SUPREME ARMY COMMAND 7 NOVEMBER, 1918
-She's a looker. -Let's see.
She's alright.
‎埃尔兹伯格先生
Herr Erzberger.
‎愿上帝与我们同在
God be with us.
‎光是过去几周 又有四万多人伤亡
Once more, over 40,000 killed in the last few weeks alone.
‎这应该能说服总参谋部
That should convince the general staff.
‎我想他们知道一切已经结束了
I think the gentlemen know it's over.
‎我们都知道
We all know that.
‎元帅来了
The General Field Marshal.
Mm.
‎（法国香槟 占领区）
CHAMPAGNE, FRANCE OCCUPIED TERRITORY
‎谢谢
-Thank you. -Jawohl.
‎不客气
‎按这个进度 保罗
Paul, if we keep up this pace,
‎我们要等180年才能征服法国
we won't have conquered France for 180 years.
‎我算过了
I worked it out.
‎你别被抓住了 凯特
Don't let them catch you, Kat.
‎绝对不会
Never.
‎你听
Come on.
‎你觉得呢 保罗？值得拼命吗？
Explain to me how this is worth dying for in your mind.
‎饿的时候什么都值得
When you're starving, you'll do anything.
Qui va là?
Ho!
Oh, putain!
Attends je vais flinguer ce fumier!
‎凯特？
Kat?
‎快跑！
Run!
‎喂！下流的德国佬！
Hey! Dirty Kraut!
‎快跑！
-Rends-moi l'oie, ordure! -Run!
Fumier!
‎你们两个真是大英雄
-Just right. -I told you.
Shut the door or the others will smell it.
‎把门关上 免得其他人闻到了
Men, you are heroes.
‎暗号
Nice work.
‎我不知道 我全忘了
I don't know. How am I supposed to remember anything?
‎用你的普鲁士脑子想一下
Come on, use your Prussian brain.
‎-这里 眼睛宽 手指长 ‎-没错
Here. Open-eyed and long-fingered.
‎嘴巴张开 鹅进肚肠！
Help me with the goose.
‎鹅鹅鹅 弗朗茨分鹅
A piece of goose from the goose. From France to Franz.
‎我要翅膀
I want a wing.
‎我一定要分享吗？剩下的给我了
Do I have to share? Then I'll take the rest.
‎大口吃吧
Fill up my bowl.
‎快来吧 你这大嘴巴鹅
Come here, you blind hen. Wide-mouth frog
‎在炮火中安息吧
-Rest in peace in the drumfire. -Ooh.
‎哦 天啊
Oh, God.
‎兄弟们 这一顿 我会终生难忘
You know I'll owe you forever for this.
Mm.
‎好吃吗？
It's not bad, is it?
‎好吃
Yes. Mm.
‎-你觉得呢？ ‎-很好吃
-And you? -Yes. Yes, good.
‎还行吧 保罗？
It's good, Paul.
‎很好 凯特
Good, Kat.
‎人生苦短
Life is short.
‎埃米尔去哪儿了？
-Where's Emil when you need him? -Emil, bring in coffee and caviar!
‎埃米尔 把咖啡和鱼子酱拿进来！
‎对 再放点泡脚水 我要泡脚
Yes, and draw my foot bath as well. I need a foot bath.
‎凯特？
-Kat? -What is it?
‎怎么了？
‎狐狸偷了鹅 把它还给我
‎把它还给我
‎-否则猎人会用… ‎-养鹅人！
-The farmer! The farmer! -The farmer! Yes!
‎养鹅人！对！
‎否则养鹅人会用步枪收拾你
‎贾登静静地坐着说：
Tjaden sits very quietly and says
‎“十字架 一天到晚就知道说十字架
"Where is he?" "Cross." I keep hearing, "Cross."
‎我父亲是拿撒勒的骑士”
"My father was leader of Nazareth."
‎“拿撒勒的骑士？” 老师问道
"Leader of Nazareth?" enquires the teacher.
‎“我从来没听说过 ‎贾登 你回家问清楚 好吗？”
"What?" "Never heard of it."
"Tjaden, go back home and ask again, will you?"
‎第二天 贾登冲进教室说：
Next morning, Tjaden springs into school and says to everybody,
‎“真是抱歉
"Please forgive me." "My father wasn't the leader of Nazareth."
‎我父亲不是拿撒勒的骑士
‎我父亲是喜欢拿沙拉里的起司”
"My father was last seen with Nadja Roth."
Brilliant.
‎快看
Look.
Mhm?
Regarder!
‎喂 你们好！
Hey! Hello!
‎过来呀！
Come here!
‎我们有长棍面包！
Fresh baguette!
‎给你们的！
For you!
‎德国肝香肠 亲爱的！
Liverwurst, love!
‎满满的爱哦！
Lots of love!
‎喂 弗朗茨 你要去哪里？
Franz. What are you doing?
‎带我一起去
-Take me with you. -Come on!
‎好 来啊！
‎你们看
I'd go over.
‎他这是在自取其辱
But he's making a fool of himself.
‎我的天啊
Oh, my. You are very beautiful, my love.
‎你好美丽啊 亲爱的
‎弗朗茨！
Franz!
‎瘦瘦的黑头发的那个是我的！
The dark-haired beauty is for me!
‎他要去哪里？
What is he doing?
‎弗朗茨？
Franz!
‎再见！
Goodbye!
‎再见 我的朋友们！
Goodbye, my friends!
‎妈的
Damn it.
‎如果一切都结束了
If it was all over, you know what I'd be doing?
‎你知道我会怎么做吗？
There's no peace, so it doesn't matter.
‎还没有和平 还没结束呢
‎我知道 假设的话
No, but if there was
‎妈的 那就又可以泡妞了
-We'd be surrounded by women again. -Yeah, that's true.
‎那倒也是
‎我一连八天都不会穿裤子
I wouldn't put trousers on for eight days.
‎你在这里说这种话 我该打你屁股了
I should really be spanking your backside for talking about something like that.
‎你呢 保罗？
What about you, Paul?
‎不知道 我想不出来
-No idea. Can't think. -I'd stay with the Prussians.
‎我会和普鲁士人待在一起
‎你疯了 贾登
You're an idiot, Tjaden.
‎你挖过泥炭吗？
Have you ever done any peat digging?
‎改天试试看
Try it sometime.
‎总不能比在香槟挖战壕更糟
Can't be worse than digging trenches in Champagne.
‎比在香槟挖战壕耗时多了
It takes longer than digging trenches in Champagne.
‎而且还不能偷懒
And you can't get away with not doing it.
‎在和平时期的军队里 你无忧无虑
In peacetime military life, you have no concerns.
‎每天早上 吃的都给你准备好
Mornings, food's there or else you're not there.
‎要不然就大闹一场
‎你还有舒服的床
And then you have the softest bed.
‎每周有新换的床单
Every week with fresh sheets over it.
‎然后
And then
‎然后你可以当士官
And before you know it, I'm a corporal.
‎想象一下
Imagine that. Me becoming a military policeman.
‎我当了一个乡警
‎这里一杯白兰地 那里一杯啤酒
A Cognac here, a pint there.
‎每个人都想和乡警搞好关系 每个人
A military policeman is everyone's good friend. Everyone.
‎但有一个问题 贾登
There's just one catch, Tjaden.
‎什么问题？
What's that?
‎你永远都当不上士官
You'll never be a corporal though, will you?
‎你净问些莫名其妙的问题
You always make such useless comments.
‎根本无济于事
What does it matter what you think anyway?
‎-凯特！ ‎-这里！
-Kat! Kat! -Here!
-Kat! -Here!
Kat!
‎“我的小胖仔
"Darling one."
‎你让我寄一包吃的过来
"You asked us for a package of food to be sent."
‎四份香肠和猪油在路上了
"Four portions of sausage are on their way with lard."
‎几个蛋糕
"A couple of pieces of cake."
‎还有酸菜和小牛肉肠
"Sauerkraut and smoked wurst."
‎还有一盒
"Some more"
‎兴…
-Hing? Hingfong? -Hingfong.
‎-兴芳止痛剂和方糖 ‎-兴芳
"and a cup of sugar."
‎一些鸡蛋和一罐李子酱
"Eggs and a glass of plum jam in there."
‎别一次吃完 我不想马上又寄一批
"Don't eat too quickly as I don't want to have to send more right away."
‎最好不要跟你的同志们分享
"I'd keep it away from your comrades if I were you."
‎我亲爱的小胖仔
"My dear one."
‎我想问你一件事
"I must also ask a question of you."
‎你目前存了多少钱？
"Have you started to save up any money?"
‎你能寄些回家吗？
"Could you send some home would you think?"
‎他们说战争很快就要结束了
"People are saying the war will be over soon." "Some people."
‎有余钱的话自然是好的
"And so it would be helpful to have some saved up."
‎现在你会想：
"You're probably thinking, 'What is she after?'"
‎‘这个老女人 脸皮真厚’
"'How cheeky of her to ask.'"
‎但我不介意
"But I mean not to offend you."
‎你知道我的 我永远都嫌不够
"You know me, I can never get enough."
‎我总是要更多 不知足是我的座右铭
"But more, more." "I can't help it, I always want some more."
‎所以你不要在终点前倒下
"So make sure not to fall over before you can come home."
‎卡尔莱默已经在东线住院了
"Karl Lemmer is in a hospital bed somewhere in the East."
‎说是肚子出了问题
"Something with his stomach."
‎他去前线还没满三周呢
"And he was out there for barely three weeks in total."
‎你有风湿 不能因为生病回家吗？
"Can't you also be sick, with your rheumatism?"
‎难道你做得还不够多吗？”
"You've already played your role."
‎要是她现在能看到你就好了
If only she could see how you're sitting there, with your cigar.
‎坐在这里抽着雪茄
‎“这个周日我会去…
"This Sunday, I'll visit the gra"
‎这个周日我会去我们小儿子的墓地
"This Sunday, I'll visit the grave of our boy."
‎我会念书给他听 他一直都很喜欢
"I'll make sure to read to him as you remember he loved that."
‎明年我们一起去 庆祝他的十岁生日
"By next year, we'll be able to celebrate his tenth birthday together."
‎好的 就说这些吧
"That's all I have to tell you this time."
‎我亲吻你 我的丈夫
"Sending kisses from your wife, for you."
‎再见”
"Auf Wiedersehen."
‎我之前都不知道
I had no idea.
‎哦 保罗
Oh, Paul.
‎接下来会怎么样？
How is all this going to work out, hmm?
‎总有一天会回家
Returning to a home,
‎回到以前的生活
having to go back to our normal being.
‎而他们只想知道 ‎我们有没有近距离作战
Where all everyone wants to know about are the battles we've been in.
‎我们会像过往风景中的过客一样
We'll be like travellers who belong in another country elsewhere.
‎我问自己
Sometimes I wonder
Would I be happier with you here at camp?
‎我是不是宁愿
Would
‎在这里和你
‎还有贾登、克罗普
Tjaden and Kropp.
‎还有穆勒坐在营火旁
And with Müller. He'd be sat with us.
‎吃炸土豆
And be eating fried potatoes.
‎连皮吃
Unpeeled.
‎是啊
Well
‎我无聊了
That's enough of that.
‎我们还要多久才能出发？
How long until we finally get going again?
‎到底还要多久？
‎弗朗茨？
Franz?
‎什么事？
Yes?
‎我们明天6点就得离开
Tomorrow, we're up at six o'clock.
‎去找几个小伙子
To look for some children.
‎出什么事了？
What happened?
‎他们应该早就到了
They should have arrived today.
‎整个连的人
A whole company.
‎你那边怎么样？
How was it?
‎嗯 很好
-Good. -Yeah?
‎是吗？
Yes.
‎是的
‎来
Here.
‎你闻闻
Have a smell.
‎她叫什么名字？
What's her name?
‎艾洛伊丝
Eloise.
‎艾洛伊丝？
‎她的皮肤 白得像牛奶
She had skin as white as milk.
‎还有她的胸…
Breasts
‎喂
-Hey. -Huh?
‎我也想闻
I want to smell it too.
‎阿尔伯特
Kropp, let me have it.
‎-克罗普 给我 ‎-你闻闻
-Here. -Oh, my.
‎-我的天啊 ‎-贾登
Give it to me.
‎像这样的姑娘连指甲缝都从不会脏
A girl like that never has dirt under her nails.
‎-对 ‎-顶多有点沙滩上的沙子
-No. -At worst, some sand from the seashore.
‎贾登
Tjaden.
‎-快点 还给我 ‎-她肯定一天要泡两次澡
-Come on, pass it here. -I bet she bathes twice a day.
‎贾登
‎拜托 这是我的
Tjaden, give it back to me.
‎贾登！
‎不给 这是我的了
Sir.
Call the others.
‎这可不是一般的炮火啊
There must have been a huge explosion.
‎这是迫击炮
Mine thrower cannons.
‎人都从军装里被炸飞了
He's been blasted right out of his uniform.
‎他是我们要找的人吗？
Was he one of those we've come here for?
‎不 他们是昨天才失踪的
No, they've only been missing since yesterday.
‎他挂那儿一段时间了
He's been hanging there for some time.
‎那倒确实
Not pleasant.
‎现在不要心软
Don't get soft now, men.
‎我们要找几个人？
How many are we looking for?
‎60名年轻新兵
Sixty young recruits.
‎早餐吃萝卜面包
Breakfast is turnip bread.
‎午餐吃萝卜面包
Same at lunchtime, it's turnip bread.
‎成天都吃萝卜面包 我受够了
I'm surrounded by turnip bread. I can't face it any more.
‎你们找到了告诉我 我一步都不想走
Let me know when you find them. I'm not going any further.
‎毒气
Gas.
‎这里有过毒气
There was gas here.
‎好嘞
Shit!
‎你好 女士
Hello, madam.
‎我是克罗普
I'm Kropp.
‎你呢？
And you?
Mm.
‎你想…
Do you want to
‎你想跟我走吗？
Do you want to come with me?
‎没问题
Not a problem.
‎凯特
Kat?
Kat.
‎凯特！
Kat!
‎妈的
Shit.
‎-这些孩子们啊 ‎-是啊
-Flipping idiots. -Uh huh.
‎他们太快摘下面具了
Stupid boys. They took their masks off too soon.
‎德国很快就会没人了
Germany will soon be empty.
‎（法国 贡比涅 1918年11月8日）
COMPIÈGNE, FRANCE 8 NOVEMBER, 1918
‎将军
General.
‎布里克斯多夫 有什么最新消息？
Well, Brixdorf, what's the latest?
‎法国人在施加压力 将军
The French are increasing the pressure.
‎今早我们的侦察员拦截到了
Early this morning, our reconnaissance intercepted orders
‎让全师兵力到拉蒂尔集结的命令
summoning entire divisions to Latierre.
‎一队坦克仍被困在费尔南库尔特
A tank fleet is still reportedly still stuck at Fernancourt.
‎我们得做好迎接袭击的准备
Must mean an attack is likely.
‎社会民主党人将是人类的末日啊
The social democrats will be the end of mankind, Brixdorf.
‎将军？
General?
‎我刚刚送德国代表团去进行停火谈判
I have just put a German delegation to the armistice negotiations
‎他们正坐火车去贡比涅
on the train to Compiègne.
‎这些人啊 布里克斯多夫
These people, Brixdorf, are selling out our fatherland.
‎他们要出卖我们的祖国
‎我的命令是战争
My orders are war.
‎只要这点不变 我必定会全力奋战
And all the while that is the case, I shall fight for every meter.
‎我们必须坚持住 等待新来的援军
We have to hold on now and wait for fresh troops.
‎再过几个月 新兵就要到了
In a few months, the incoming class of recruits will be here.
‎法国人想将那些狗屁条件强加于我们
The French are trying everything they can
to force their completely unacceptable terms on us.
‎我不会投降
I will not capitulate.
‎我们现在必须出击
We must strike without delay. With all our might.
‎全力出击
‎是 将军
General.
‎以我们的立场
From our position,
‎我坚持要求…
I have to be clear
‎我们坚持要求…
We all have to be clear
‎妈的
For God's sake.
‎真他妈的
Shit.
‎中尉
Sir!
‎士兵们 快收拾东西
Soldiers, pack your bags,
‎把铺盖被罩卷好 把炊具餐具洗了
roll up your bedding, and wash your mess kits.
‎整个团都要向前线进发
The whole regiment will advance to the front firing position.
‎凡是两只腿可以站起来的人都要去
And I mean everyone who's able to stand on two legs is going.
‎快点排好队 妈的！
Line up, for God's sake.
‎难道法国人会等着你们梳阴毛吗？
You think the Frenchies will wait for you to comb your pubes?
‎我们又要走了
-Here we go again. -Get moving!
‎-快点！ ‎-去哪里？
-Where to? -Where to? Where to?
‎“去哪里？”
‎去打仗啊
Into battle.
‎元帅在等各位过去
Monsieur le Maréchal is awaiting you.
‎我很快就回来
I'll come back for you.
‎嫉妒吧？
Envious, huh?
‎我站在你们面前
I stand before you
‎是希望你们能将我们的到访
in the hope that you will take our presence here today as an opportunity
‎看作暂停一切敌对活动的契机
to take action to suspend all hostilities.
‎以人性之名
In the name of humanity,
‎我请你们同意立即停火
I'm here asking you for an agreement to an immediate cease-fire
‎在整个谈判期间都不交战
for the entire duration of our negotiating time
‎以免我们各自的国家有不必要的损失
in order to spare our nation's unnecessary depletion.
‎马蒂亚斯埃尔兹伯格
Matthias Erzberger, head of the German delegation.
‎德国代表团团长
Weygand, what do these gentlemen want?
I don't know.
‎福煦元帅问诸位此行的目的是什么
Marshal Foch asks what brings you gentlemen to him.
‎我们想听听您的建议
We are here looking forward to hearing
‎看看如何达成最终的停火
your proposal for an enduring cease-fire
‎陆、海、空全线停火
that will include all those on the water, on land, as well as in the sky.
‎我对你们没有任何建议
I have no proposal of this kind to make.
‎他这是何意？
What does he mean by that?
‎我觉得他可能不喜欢您的措辞
I think he disliked the phrasing of what you said.
‎好吧
Yes.
‎那么 这个…
Good, then
‎元帅先生
Monsieur Le Maréchal,
‎如果您愿意
If you please, we would like to know the conditions--
‎我们想知道具体条件
‎他想让您正式提出请求
He wants you to ask for it, formally.
‎元帅先生
Monsieur le Maréchal,
‎我请求您停战
I am asking you for an armistice.
We are asking for an armistice.
You have 72 hours to accept our conditions.
‎你们有72小时接受我们的条件
‎没有商量的余地
They are non-negotiable.
‎-72小时？ ‎-战争将持续到您签字为止
Seventy-two hours?
The war will continue until you sign them.
‎元帅先生
Monsieur le Maréchal,
‎以上帝之名 别让战争再持续72小时
in God's name, don't let 72 hours pass us by here.
‎很多人已经丧命
Thousands of lives depend on it.
‎那就签字吧
Sign then.
‎明白了
Understood.
‎让士兵们前进
-Soldiers, we'll march. -Sir.
‎士兵们 前进
Soldiers, march.
‎前进吧 士兵们
March, soldiers.
‎士兵们 前进
Soldiers, march.
‎走吧 快上去
Off you go, get out of here.
‎前进吧 士兵们
March, soldiers.
‎前进
March.
‎士兵们 前进
Soldiers, march.
‎士兵们 前进 快走
March, soldiers. Off you go.
‎冲啊！
‎-快点！ ‎-冲啊！
‎进攻！
‎上！
‎冲啊！
‎保持队形！
‎不要停！
‎快！
Go, go, go!
Atención aux arbalètes
Allez! Allez les gars!
Allez! Allez!
‎我们走 保罗 快！
Keep going, Paul. Come on. Paul!
‎保罗！
Allez!
Au renfort!
Putain, putain, non, non!
Get out!
What is that?
‎快出去！
Get out!
-Here! -Quick, quick, quick! Move it!
There, there, look!
-What is it? -Down there.
What is it?
‎开火！
Open fire!
‎趴下！
All down!
Get down!
‎快找掩护！
‎快出去！
‎原地不动 紧密作战！
Boys, think fast! Be smart!
‎手榴弹！
Get the hand grenades out!
‎他们开到上面的时候 瞄准履带！
Throw them in the vehicle when they're on top of us.
‎走 兄弟们！
‎快走 弗朗茨
‎弗朗茨！
Get out!
‎跟我走！
Get up!
‎弗朗茨！
Franz!
‎来 跟我来！
Follow me. Come on, follow me!
‎弗朗茨！
Franz!
‎保罗！
Paul!
‎冲啊！
‎保罗
Paul.
‎保罗！
Paul!
‎开火！
Open fire!
‎撤退！
Retreat!
‎不要！别开枪！
No, no, no! Don't shoot! Don't shoot! No!
‎不要！
Please, please, no! No, no, no!
‎不要！别开枪！
No, wait, wait, don't shoot. Don't shoot. Don't shoot. No.
‎阿尔伯特
-No, no! -Albert.
Come on, come on.
‎快走！
Come on!
‎别停下！
Keep going!
‎弗朗茨在哪里？
Where is Franz?
‎弗朗茨不见了！
I've left Franz alone!
‎凯特因斯基！
Katczinsky!
‎拿好机枪就撤退！
Take the machine gun and retreat.
‎然后往东北两公里到伊吉萨克集合！
We'll regroup in Eguisac, two kilometres northeast.
‎我想念我的同伴了 中士！
I miss my comrades, sir. I miss them all!
‎我还想我妈呢 妈的！
I miss my mother, for God's sake.
‎拿上手榴弹和弹药 我们走！
Grenades, ammunition! Come on!
‎保罗 快走！
Paul, come on!
Get out of here! Let's go!
‎这些不是谈判条件 而是律令
These aren't negotiations, this is a dictate.
‎也许我们应该回斯帕 ‎跟总参谋部商量一下
Maybe we should return to Spa to consult with the general staff.
‎您觉得那会有什么用？
And what expectations do you have for that?
‎就算我们最终输了
Even if we end up losing definitively after all,
‎结果也不会比投降更糟
we won't be worse off than we are with this surrender.
‎但是会多死掉几十万人
Except for a few hundred thousand extra deaths.
‎阿尔萨斯洛林、占领莱因河
Alsace-Lorraine, occupation of the Rhineland,
‎大炮、机车、火车
cannons, locomotives, trains, and whatever else.
‎这是彻彻底底的投降啊！
You are aware, this is a total capitulation.
‎每个月有25万美国人来到欧洲
250,000 Americans are landing each month in Europe.
‎马恩、坎蒂尼、康布雷 全部输了
Marne, Cantigny, Cambrai. All of those lost.
‎唯一阻碍我们停火的就是虚无的自尊
All that's left separating us from an armistice
is false pride, as I see it.
‎是时候该处理您和将军们的烂摊子了
Thanks to you and your commanders,
we're here dealing with the mess left by them.
‎但如果您想离开 那么请便
I'm happy for you to depart here, it's down to you.
‎我们会留在这里
We are remaining here.
‎现在是冬天
It is winter.
‎没了火车和物资 ‎布尔什维克会击垮我们
Without trains and provisions, Bolshevism will take over.
‎士兵们会在回家的路上饿死
On their way home, the men will die of hunger
‎而不是在战场上光荣战死
instead of dying with honour on the battlefield.
‎光荣战死？
Honour?
‎我儿子战死了 但他并不感到光荣
My son was killed in the war. He doesn't feel any honour.
‎冯海尔道夫
Von Helldorf.
‎请把协约国所提要求的副本 ‎通过电报发给总部
Please get a few copies of the conditions of their proposal
and telegraph them to headquarters.
‎你去通知政府
You inform the government.
‎诸位 我们有72个小时
We have 72 hours left here, gentlemen,
‎每浪费一分钟 就又有一个士兵死去
and during every minute we waste by talking about it,
there dies another soldier.
‎我们接受能得到的慈悲吧
Let us gain mercy where we can, but for God's sake,
‎但是 看在上帝的份上
‎我们停战求和吧
let's make peace.
‎撤退！
Retreat! Retreat!
‎他们撤退了！加强火力！
Run! Run!
‎加强火力！
Keep firing!
‎别出声！
Shut up!
‎闭嘴！
That's enough!
‎不要
No, no, no.
‎同志
Comrade.
Comrade, comrade.
‎同志
‎对不起
So sorry.
‎真对不起
I am so sorry. I am so sorry.
‎（杰拉德杜瓦尔 排字员）
DUVAL, GÉRARD TYPOGRAPHER
‎你的家
Your wife
‎你的妻子
‎我保证
I promise I promise
‎我保…
I promise
‎你什么时候出生的 布里克斯多夫？
When were you born, Brixdorf?
‎1877年6月
1877, in June.
‎夏天出生的孩子
A summer child.
‎是的
Yes.
‎你父亲是做什么的？
What about your father?
‎我家在荷尔斯泰因有一间工坊
My family live in Holstein and he has a factory there.
‎什么样的工坊？
Producing what?
‎骑马用的马鞍 将军
Riding saddles, general.
‎马鞍
Riding saddles.
‎马鞍永远有销路
Something that will always sell. Your future is secure then.
‎您的未来很有保障
‎我很幸运
I am indeed fortunate.
‎那么
And?
‎你期盼着回家吗？
Are you looking forward to going home?
‎当这里不再需要我们的时候？
-When we are no longer needed here? -Yes.
‎是的
‎战后有一份工作等着我
After the war, a position of responsibility awaits me.
‎我会接手家里的生意
-I will take over the business. -Mhm.
‎恭喜
Congratulations.
‎您呢？
And you?
‎我是个战士
I'm a soldier.
‎我父亲曾是一个团的军官
My father was an officer in this regiment.
‎他参加了俾斯麦领导的三场战争
He fought in the three wars under Bismarck.
‎他三场都赢了
He won all three of them.
‎他在1871年率军挺进巴黎
In 1871, he marched on Paris
‎然后英雄凯旋
and when he returned, he was a hero.
‎我生不逢时啊 布里克斯多夫
I was too late in being born, Brixdorf.
‎半个世纪都没有战争
It's been 50 years of no war.
‎没有战争 那战士有何用？
What is a soldier without war?
‎您跟您父亲亲近吗？
Were you and your father close?
‎或许小时候还行吧
As a child, maybe.
‎独自来到世上的男人
A man is alone when born.
‎独自活着
He lives alone
‎独自死去
and on his deathbed is alone.
‎（德国皇帝宣告退位）
THE KAISER HAS ABDICATED
‎进来
Come in.
‎冯海尔道夫 什么事？
-Von Helldorf. How can I help you? -Hindenburg.
‎兴登堡来函
Open it immediately.
‎快快打开
‎他在催我们签字
He urges us to sign.
‎结束了！
-It's over! -We're going home!
We're going home!
Back to our families.
In the name of all who are living in a world of sin.
We are surrounded by it now in the filth.
‎敲开修道院的门
Knock on the monastery's door
‎你只会发现小偷和无赖
and you'll find only thieves and scoundrels.
‎都结束了 那些肥猪终于意识到了
It's finally over. The fat pigs finally get it.
‎他们终于在谈判了
They're negotiating at last. We're going home soon, do you hear that?
‎我们马上就要回家了 战士！
‎医务室在哪里？
Are there any sergeants left?
‎不要！
Chloroform the man, for God's sake.
‎快给他上氯仿麻醉！
‎博伊默尔
Bäumer.
‎-贾登 ‎-博伊默尔
Tjaden? Tjaden.
‎怎么回事？你哪里受伤了？
What happened?
Above the knee.
‎膝盖上面
Where have you been hit?
‎好像是
Or somewhere down there.
‎我什么都感觉不到
I can't feel anything.
‎伤口离膝盖有多远？
How far up is the shot?
‎我没办法抬头看
I can't raise my head.
‎至少10厘米吧
Ten centimetres, it seems.
‎你要回家了 贾登
You're going home soon, Tjaden.
‎-是吗？ ‎-肯定的
-You think so? -Yes, you are.
‎我这样要怎么当乡警？
It's unlikely the police force will have me, though.
‎真他妈的
God damn shit.
‎你还是可以的
You can still do it.
‎你等着瞧
Just wait and see.
‎我不会让他们截肢的
I'm not going to let them amputate me.
‎我绝对不要瘸着过活
I'm not living as a cripple in this world.
‎不需要的
You won't have to.
‎他们处理过比这还糟糕得多的
There are others who are worse off that they've patched up.
‎哦 保罗
Oh, dear Paul.
‎我应该给你一样东西
I have something to give you.
‎他死了吗？
Is he dead?
‎你必须得勇敢起来
You must show braveness.
‎你还活着
You're alive, remember?
‎你一定要心怀感激
For that, you have to be grateful.
‎为了我们
For us.
‎为了那些没能活下来的人
-For those who didn't make it. -That's enough.
‎别说了
Look here. You mustn't say that. Not you.
‎听着 你不可以这么说 你不可以！
Good feeling, right?
Have a bit of that, then.
Yeah, dry your socks out there.
The way the last summer was
Right, none
You see?
Not like the last one.
That was too
You always blame me.
-We saw you! --What did you see me doing?
Come on!
Nah, we know it was you.
Why is it always on me?
‎我知道你们要吃饭 但人还没到齐
‎你喂不上他们了 ‎他们不在医务室就在墓地
‎快点舀饭 我们闻得出已经好了
‎那不行
‎为什么不行 你个无赖？
‎我煮了150个人的份
‎150个人的不能只给80个人吃
‎你是脑子有屎吗？
Do you have shit for brains? Why won't you listen?
‎你收到了第二连队的口粮
You have been given a second company's provisions.
‎我们就是第二连队！
We are that second company!
‎对！
So dish it out! Give it to us!
‎快点给饭吧 快点！
‎凯特！
Kat?
‎-凯特！ ‎-保罗！
-Kat! -Paul?
‎凯特！
Kat!
‎保罗！
Paul!
‎凯特 你还活着
-Paul! -Kat, you were alive.
‎你还活着
-Paul! -You're alive!
‎保罗
Paul.
‎贾登中弹了
Tjaden was hit.
‎他在教堂里躺着
He's lying inside the church.
‎我们给他拿双份的饭
He'll get a double portion from us.
‎对 来吧
Yes.
‎小心
‎再来一份
Another one. In here.
‎妈的 我还以为你死了呢
-I thought you were dead. -Ha!
‎人迟早都要死
At some point, we'll all die.
‎但不能在就要回家时死
But not on the home stretch.
‎如果你死在我前头 我会杀了你
If you die before me, I'll kill you.
Ha!
‎贾登
Tjaden.
Yes.
‎-凯特？ ‎-对
-Kat? -Yes.
‎凯特
Kat.
‎我们拿了点汤来
I've soup here for you.
‎有餐具吗？
Have you brought cutlery?
‎有 餐具也拿了
Yes, we brought cutlery as well.
‎吃吧
There you go. Eat up.
‎不要 住手 贾登！
Stop, stop, Tjaden, Tjaden!
‎贾登 住手！
Stop!
‎快来人啊！
We need help over here!
‎你为什么要这么做？
What made you do that?
‎为什么？
Why would you?
‎结束了 兄弟们 都结束了
It's over for me.
‎他血快流光了！
He's bleeding out!
‎贾登
Tjaden.
‎怎么了？
What is it?
‎我有样东西不见了
I've lost something.
‎凯特 你会说法语吗？
Kat, do you speak French?
‎比如“请”
Mm. S'il vous plaît. S'il vous plaît.
‎我母亲当初要我学法语来着
My mother always said it was French I should learn.
‎这样啊
Aha.
‎还有钢琴
And the piano.
‎她不希望我上战场
She also warned me of war.
‎她说：“那不是你该做的
She didn't want me to go.
‎你没几天就会死”
"That's not for you," she always said. "You'll be dead in no time."
‎我想向他们证明我能做到
I wanted to show that I could do it.
‎结果我们是这种境遇
What use is that now?
‎还说什么再过几周就到巴黎了
"A couple of weeks, we'll be in Paris."
‎不断扔手榴弹的这两年
These past two years of grenades can't be shed like an item of clothing.
‎可不像臭袜子说脱就脱
‎保罗
-Paul. -The stench will remain on us forever.
‎我们永远无法去除这股恶臭
‎-够了 ‎-路德维希死了 弗朗茨死了
-Enough. -Ludwig is dead. Franz is dead. Albert--
‎-阿尔伯特… ‎-这关我们什么事？
Is that to do with us?
‎他们安息了
They don't suffer any more.
‎我们还活着
Peace for them.
We're still alive.
‎这里的一切就像发烧一样
Everything here is like a fever.
‎没人真的想要发烧 但它突然就来了
Not one person wants it but suddenly it's there.
‎我们不想要 其他人也不想要
We didn't ask for it. The others didn't ask for it.
‎但我们来了 全世界也卷进来一半
But nonetheless it happened
and nonetheless half the world is involved, mind you.
‎上帝就这样看着
God looks down
‎看着我们彼此屠杀
at us murderers.
‎就是这样
Yeah, well.
‎但我又知道什么呢？
But what do I know?
‎我什么都不知道
Nothing.
‎我是一双带着步枪的靴子
I'm a pair of boots with a rifle.
‎去睡吧 我们运气好
Get some rest. We're the lucky ones.
‎好
Yes.
‎凯特？
Kat?
‎嗯？
Mm.
‎你儿子是怎么死的？
What did your son die of?
‎天花
The pox.
‎我害怕接下来会发生的事
I'm afraid of what's to come.
‎别怕
Don't be.
‎亨利
Henri.
‎尝尝
Taste it.
‎这是今天做的吗？
Were they made today?
‎对不起 先生 应该不是
I'm sorry, sir. I don't think so.
Hmm.
Monsieur le Maréchal.
‎我听着呢
I'm listening.
‎皇帝已经退位了
The Kaiser has abdicated.
‎士兵们拒绝服从命令
Soldiers are refusing to obey orders. Deserters are roaming the countryside.
‎逃兵在乡下游荡
‎新政府将尽全力履行需要担当的职责
The new government will do everything it can
to fulfil the duties imposed on it,
‎但是并没有犯错的平民百姓
but the population, through no fault of its own,
‎却可能面临饥荒和无政府混乱
faces hunger and anarchy setting in.
‎这是败者的问题 而非胜者的问题
This is a disease of the defeated, not of the victorious.
‎我不怕
I don't fear it.
‎我拒绝任何妥协
I reject any compromise.
‎元帅先生 拜托了
Monsieur le Maréchal, please.
‎请公平对待您的对手 ‎否则和平会令其愤懑
Be fair to your opponent or else this peace will be hated.
‎公平？
Fair?
‎您还要谈公平？
You speak of fairness?
‎签字吧
Sign it.
‎会议记录将写明
Let the minutes record.
‎停战协议将在六小时后
The armistice here signed shall take effect in six hours from now
‎即11月11日的上午11点生效
at the eleventh hour, on the eleventh day of the eleventh month.
‎很好
Very good.
‎战争结束了
The war is over.
‎您现在打算怎么做？
What are you going to do now?
‎你看到了什么 布里克斯多夫？
What do you see here, Brixdorf?
‎拉蒂尔平原 将军
The plains of Latierre, general.
‎伊吉萨克
Eguisac.
‎我也看到了
I see them too.
‎还有德国士兵 像兔子一样逃跑
But also German soldiers running away like cowards.
‎法国人在拉蒂尔打得我们屁滚尿流
The French troops are farting on our position in Latierre
‎外面还有一火车的王八蛋
and outside there's a train crammed full of horse fuckers
‎想要出卖祖国
who are selling the homeland off.
‎让所有新兵撤离兵营
See to it that all recruits are withdrawn.
‎让他们到院子里报到
Have them all report here.
‎我们他妈的要收拾这个烂摊子！
We're going to sort out this pile of shit!
‎继续严禁与敌人进行一切通讯
Any communication with the enemy remains prohibited.
‎第一 西线所有敌对行动于今日停止
Firstly, hostilities on the entire front will be ceased this morning,
‎从11月11日上午11点起生效
November 11th at eleven o'clock.
‎第二 全体部队禁止继续前进
Secondly, the troops will not cross the line reached
‎就停留在今日此刻的位置
on this day at this hour.
The front line shall remain unchanged past this hour.
All troops are to return to their station.
‎几点了？
What time is it?
‎你怎么不睡啊？
-Why aren't you asleep? -Listen a minute.
‎你听
‎好安静啊
It's so still.
‎就像我耳聋了一样
I must be going deaf.
‎他们已经签字了 保罗
They've signed, Paul.
‎战争结束了
The war's over.
‎结束了
It's over.
‎你饿了吗？
Are you hungry?
‎我饿了
I'm hungry.
‎你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
‎快点 趁那个混蛋还没醒
Come on, before the bastard wakes up.
‎你圣诞节做什么 保罗？
-What are you doing for Christmas, Paul? -I don't know.
‎不知道
I'm gonna roast a goose.
‎我要烤鹅吃
‎配上红甘蓝和土豆
Red cabbage, potatoes
‎然后我要点上所有蜡烛
Then I'll light all the candles and kiss my wife.
‎再亲吻我的老婆
My God, Paul, she is beautiful.
‎哎 保罗 我老婆可漂亮了
‎-是吗？ ‎-对
Yeah?
‎她长什么样？
-What does she look like? -Well
‎嗯
Long curly hair, dark.
‎长卷发 深色的
‎而且她又圆又结实
And she's buxom and strong.
Yeah?
‎圣诞节
Christmas.
‎好遥远啊
It's all so far away still.
‎其实并不遥远 很快就到了
No, it's not. It's really close.
‎我们想再要一个孩子
We want another child. Or children, Paul.
‎好几个孩子 保罗
Because what is Christmas without children? It's nothing, really.
‎没有孩子的圣诞节算什么？没意义
‎对吧？
Ah?
‎你知道的
You know when
‎等我们回家了
Once we're back home, then we will
‎-嗯？ ‎-我们要干点大事
-Yeah? -We must do something together.
‎我们两个一起 好吗？
The two of us together. Something big, yeah?
‎唉
Yeah, yeah.
‎怎么了？
What is it?
‎我是补鞋匠 保罗
I'm a shoemaker, Paul. I repair shoes.
‎我是修鞋的 懂吗？
Ah? You know how to read, write. You finished school.
‎你懂得读书写字 你有高中文凭
‎但也没什么用啊
Hasn't done me any good, though.
‎那我们做什么？
What are we gonna do?
‎给鞋子钉鞋底 我们两个？
Sole shoes together?
‎你是想羞辱我吗？
Are you trying to insult me?
‎我连我老婆的信都看不懂
I can't read my wife's letters even now.
‎你要去读书 保罗
You're going to university, Paul.
‎不然我现在就毙了你
Or I'll shoot you right here.
‎我的裤子要掉了
My trousers are loose.
‎我的裤子松了
‎你多吃一点就好了
You'll just have to eat something.
‎很快我们就回家了 想吃什么随便吃
Soon we'll be home then we can eat whatever we want.
‎随便吃
Whatever we want.
‎该你了
It's your go.
‎如果养鹅的再发现我的话
If the farmer catches me again,
‎他应该会开枪打我
then he's bound to shoot me down where I stand.
‎小心那条臭狗
Just be careful of the damn dog too.
‎好的
Yeah.
Ah?
‎嘘
Shh, shh Hey, hey, hey.
‎你看
Look.
‎真的很不错
It's really good.
‎你要吗？
Want some?
‎妈的
Shit.
Piece of garbage
Stop!
‎站住！
Thief!
‎凯特
Kat! Run!
‎快跑！
Run!
‎王八蛋！
Asshole!
‎妈的
God damn!
We'll kill them, these sons of bitches.
‎哦 他妈的
Oh, crap.
‎快看
-Look at this. -What is it?
‎怎么了？
-A lucky shot. -He hit the eggs!
‎我运气太好了
‎打的是蛋吗？
‎-用手按着 ‎-好
Stop the flow.
‎-全都倒进去 ‎-好
Come on, get it in there.
‎全倒进去
There you go.
‎我们可以煎了吃
We can have an omelette.
‎胡说八道 我们现在就吃
No, we'll eat them now.
‎这样也行
They're just as good.
‎这味道简直了
Better than ever.
‎我马上回来
I won't be long.
‎凯特？
Kat?
‎凯特
Kat!
‎怎么了？
What happened?
‎我们走
We should leave.
‎谁开的枪？
Who fired the shot?
‎养鹅场的小屁孩
That little shit from the farm.
‎养鹅户的儿子
The farmer's son.
‎凯特
Kat, Kat.
‎真是一团糟
What a mess.
‎有多大？
How big is it?
‎小手指那么大
Little finger. I'll get the bullet out.
‎我把子弹弄出来
No. Give me a cigarette.
‎不 给我一根烟就好
‎让医护员来吧
Let the medic do that.
‎他们让我和七岁的孩子一起上课
They stuck me in a class with seven-year-olds.
‎我当时已经开始刮胡子了
I'd begun shaving already.
‎找一个跟“骨气”押韵的词
Find me a word.
That trifle can rhyme with.
Mhm.
‎没有词和骨气押韵啊 没有
Nothing rhymes with trifle. Nothing.
‎真他妈的
Fucking shit.
‎为什么要偏偏挑这个时候？
Why the hell did this have to happen now?
‎-来吧 我们得走了 ‎-好
-Come on, we need to move. -Yeah.
‎走吧
‎你可以吗 凯特？
Alright?
Kat?
‎武器
Rifle.
‎嗯？
Mhm?
‎武器和骨气押韵
Rifle rhymes with trifle.
‎回家之后 你得给我做一双新靴子
When we get home, you're going to make a new pair of boots for me.
‎我的脚都走出血了
I'm walking my feet to the bone.
‎停车！
Hey!
Wait!
‎快停下！
Pull over!
Let us on!
‎快停下！
Hey! Let us on!
Come on, will you?
‎医护员！
This man needs care.
Where is the medic?
‎其实你不用白费力气
Could've spared yourself the trouble.
‎啊？
Huh?
‎他死了
He's dead.
‎可是 那只是一个很小的枪伤
But it's It's just a small bullet wound.
‎对 血都黑了 直接进入了肝脏
Yes, black blood. Straight into the liver.
‎器官中毒了
The organs are poisoned.
‎他是昏过去了
Unconscious.
‎不
No.
‎他死了
He's dead.
‎这个我应该比你懂
I know what I'm doing.
‎不可能 我刚才还跟他说话来着
Impossible. I was I was just talking to him.
‎他是昏过去了
He's unconscious.
‎你看到了吗？
See?
‎他很倒霉 眼看就要到终点了
He simply had bad luck. Right before the end.
‎走吧 士兵
‎将军让我们回家了
‎我们要回家了！
Go on, keep going!
‎快走！
Keep going!
‎快一点！
Keep going, come on!
This is it.
I'm going to tell him I'm going home.
It's over.
‎立正！
Attention!
‎战士们
Soldiers.
‎我们作为兄弟站在这里
We stand here as brothers
‎在敌人的世界里
in a world of enemies
‎我们被迫看着德国社会民主党人
and are forced to watch as German social democrats
render our beloved people defenseless
‎让我们亲爱的人民毫无还手之力
‎因为他们接受了卑鄙叛国的停战协议
by accepting a perfidious armistice.
‎同志们
Comrades.
‎很快你们就会回家
Soon you will be going home
‎见到你们的父母、妻子和孩子
to your parents, wives and children.
‎战争结束了
The war is over.
‎你们多年的牺牲和磨难终有好的回报
After years of sacrifice and suffering, you can now look forward to your reward.
‎那就是你们在这里赢得的尊敬
To the reward of admiration for all you have achieved here.
‎但是 同志们
Ah, but comrades,
‎你们想被当成战士和英雄受到欢迎
do you want to be welcomed as soldiers and heroes on your return
‎还是被视作在关键时刻退缩的懦夫？
or as weaklings
and cowards who tucked their tails in when it really counted?
‎士兵们
We're going home.
Soldiers.
‎我们要竭尽全力向他们发动进攻
We are about to attack them with the utmost force and vehemence.
‎拉蒂尔属于德国人
Latierre belongs in German hands.
‎我们要在11点前占领平原
We will seize the plains before 11:00 a.m. and end this war with a merciless strike.
‎让这场战争
‎以胜利告终！
and make them see
‎冲啊！
we were victorious.
‎上帝会与我们同在
Onwards, with God on our side as he was with our fathers before us.
‎就像他与我们的父辈同在一样
‎我不会回去战斗的 我不干！
I'm not going back into battle. Not me!
‎闭嘴！
Shut up!
-Let me go! -Follow your orders!
Do as your told!
All of you, get back.
-Please, I didn't do anything! -Aim!
‎瞄准！
-No! No! -Fire!
‎不要！
‎开火！
Keep moving!
Come on!
‎全连人员 停下！
Company, halt!
‎取下步枪！
Rifle off!
‎装上刺刀！
-Fix bayonets! -Fix bayonets and load!
‎几点了？
What time is it?
‎还有15分钟
Fifteen minutes to go.
‎这是勒菲弗的
It belonged to Lefèvre.
‎那可怜的小子想留到结束时喝的
Poor bastard, he saved it for the end.
‎他再也不需要了
-He won't need it anymore. -Thank you, sir.
‎谢谢长官
‎敬您和勒菲弗
Here's to you and to Lefèvre.
‎真好喝
Well, it's good.
‎噩梦结束了
The nightmare is over.
‎有敌人进攻！
Enemy attack! Enemy attack!
‎-全体就位！ ‎-全体就位！
-In position! -In position!
‎开火！
Fire!
‎手榴弹！
Throw the grenades!
‎进攻！
Charge!
‎不要！
Please, no! No, no!
‎不 不要啊！
‎停火！
Cease fire!
‎11点了！
It is 11:00 a.m.!
‎停火！
Cease fire!
‎11点了！
It is eleven o'clock.
A light! Bring me a light! A light please!
‎你还好吧 士兵？
Are you alright?
‎嗯
Yeah.
‎那么请开始收集吧
Well, then. Start gathering, please.
‎（1914年10月开始敌对行动后不久）
Shortly after the start of hostilities in October 1914,
‎（西线就陷入了堑壕战）
the Western Front froze into positional warfare.
‎（直到1918年11月战争结束之时）
By the end of the war in November 1918, the front line had barely moved.
‎（前线几乎没有移动）
‎（超过300万士兵在这里丧生）
More than three million soldiers died here,
‎（通常只是为了挺进几百米而奋战）
often while fighting to gain only a few hundred meters of ground.
‎（将近1700万人在一战中丧生）
Almost 17 million people lost their lives in the First World War.
‎片名：西线无战事
ALL QUIET ON THE WESTERN FRONT
‎字幕翻译：先思瑾